Car insurance claims are remembered only after an
accident has occurred.  But if you
follow the wrong steps, this claim
is guaranteed to be rejected.  So in this video we will
understand what is the exact process and
what things you have to keep in mind and what
mistakes you should not make.  So let us first understand
why many insurance claims get rejected
or fail in India.  Friends, the
biggest point is that after an accident, the
decisions are taken in great panic.
They do not understand what to do and what
not to do.  They inform the insurance company very
late.  After that, there are many people
like if your car gets
damaged somewhere, they get it repaired outside
and then they expect that the
insurance company will give them the claim and
during this process, either they
give wrong information or if there are details, they do
not complete them at all.  And as far as the main
thing is concerned, they do not understand
what is the process of car insurance?  So let us understand what
you should do after an accident.
See, safety comes first.  So
you have to see that if only the car is
damaged then it is okay.  But if you have been
hurt or injured, first of all
call the ambulance.  You should
go to the doctor and get yourself treated first.  If
only the car is hit, then first of all you have to
park the car on the side.  You have to see
what the location is?  Where is the car
damaged?  Whose fault was it?  It was yours, it was
someone else's.  That's a matter for later, but you have to calm
down your mood.  First of all you have to
take a clear photo of the vehicle.  If
possible make a video.  You can say in the video
that it has been so long now.  This
is the location and my car has been touched here and the
car has been damaged here and here.
So what happens with all this?
You make the work of the insurance company very easy.
Even if they inspect later,
they come to know that
something had happened here at this time.  So you have to take these things
very carefully.  After that, you have to
call your insurance company at the same time
and inform them that
my car has met with an accident or has been
damaged at this time and at this location.  If they
start that intimacy from there, then
your work becomes easier later on.
But if you do this thing
after 10, 20, 25 days then they
ask you why did you wait so much
?  What was the region?  So the
insurance claim process becomes very
hard for you and in many chances
it may get rejected.  They
may say that you did not cause this damage yourself, so they will
not be able to answer this.   So,
whenever an accident happens,
take precautions.  Take proper photos.
Park the car on the side.  Make a video.
See what the place is?  What is location?  And
call your insurance company at the same time.
So we have to understand what are the
types of car insurance.  See, the first one
is cashless and the second one is
reimbursement.  See, both of them work on
claims but the process of both is different.   The
documentation for both is different.  The flow of both
is different.  What is encashment?   There is
an insurance approved garage here.
Wherever you get the work done and whatever
is insured and your claim
process happens automatically and very
smoothly.  As far as reimbursement is concerned, what happens is that
you first get the car repaired.
Collect all the bills.
Someone is called for the survey.
After that,
you show the money you have spent to your insurance company
and then it gives you the money.  So this
is the difference between cashless and reimbursement.
You must understand that cashless means that here you do
not have to pay any money and in reimbursement, you have to
pay the money first and then
return it to you later.  The process
is the same for both but people are very confused as to
which one to take and which one not to take.  As far as
choosing these is concerned, I would recommend
that you should always go for cashless insurance.
Because this has happened to me personally
when my car was damaged.
So this is the process and the
steps that I took and it was very
smooth.  I had to make just one or two phone calls
and all the back end work of
money transfer, insurance claim,
damage fixation, all that was done
very easily and my
insurance company and their garage
which they had approved or with whom
they had a tie up, they coordinated very well and got
my car repaired.
So on a personal level, I would
say that cashless is a very
smooth and good process.  As far as
reimbursement is concerned, this is also good.  Here you have to get the
work done yourself first.  You yourself have to
tell the company where the damage has occurred.
You have to collect the bills.
You have to call a survey inspector.
He first surveys your car.
After that you can go and get the car repaired.
So this process is
also correct.  But the documentation,
timeline and your
involvement in this increases a lot.
So it is your personal choice where you want to go
and how you want to do it.  But on a personal
level, I would say that cashless is much
better as compared to reimbursement.  So now let us
see what documents they are going to
ask from you.  Now you know whether
your insurance was cashless or
reimbursement based.  Now the documents are
broadly the same and the
process flow is different.  You have to keep in
mind that you should have your driving
license, RC of the vehicle,
all the papers of the vehicle, whatever insurance
paper comes to you, you should have that with you as you pay.  You have
mentioned the proper claims in it.  And if another vehicle
was involved there, if the police came there, then
you will also need a copy of the FIR.  Because these are the
things.  The insurance company may ask you for this
before starting your repair.
And now about reimbursement.  If you are due for
reimbursement, you need to keep all the bills
safe.  If you are getting your
car service done from outside, from some other garage
, you have to keep each and every bill safe.
Because you have to submit everything at the end.
And this
process becomes automatic if you have
cashless insurance.  The
insurance approved garage there itself
calls the survey inspector.  He comes and
tells the estimate on one side.  After that the
insured sells the money to the garage.   The
garage does all the work and delivers the car to you.  So that's why
I say
that cashless is very smooth as compared
to reimbursement.  But there is reimbursement.  You have to keep in
mind that you should have all the bills and
receipts properly.   Only
after that you will be able to get your insurance claim.
If even one document is missing
then there could be some confusion.
Take special care of this.  Now let us talk about
some common reasons due to which the
rejection of claims increases.   First of all
it increases inside the drink and drive
case.  If you have drunk and driven, then
more than 90% of the companies do
not give you any claim.  Because
you were the one responsible here.  You put your own life
in danger and
you also put the lives of the people walking in the traffic in danger.
So it is very difficult to make an insurance claim in a drink and drive case.   The
second point is that many of the
drivers are not authorized
for the vehicle.  For example, if someone is underage and does
not have a license, or if the driver
is not authorized to drive the car, then this
becomes a big issue in making your insurance
claim.  The third point is that
they make late intimation due to which the
insurance company feels that if this person is making
insurance claim after so much time then there
is something wrong.  So do not make this mistake at all.
As soon as an accident occurs,
you should directly call your insurance
company and get this work done as soon as possible.   The
fourth point is that sometimes
many people in India get their vehicles
modified and sometimes when the
modifications are done, they are very unauthorized
and the dealers are not even aware that
such modifications have been done in our car.
So even at that time they can reject this thing.
Because if you are
modifying a car, then the
overall aerodynamics of the car or the
build quality of the car are being tampered with,
so this becomes a big reason.  If
you make modifications to an undeclared vehicle.
And the last point is that many people's
policies expire or lapse
and they do not get them renewed.
I have talked about this point earlier but I
want to add it here again.
Because this is very common.
Your policy expires after one year.  Many
people do not receive the message.  Just change your phone
number or email ID.  So
they don't even know that my
insurance has expired.  So
guys make sure you pay attention to this.
Either set a reminder on your phone for after a year
or do something to remind you
when you need to renew your policy.
Because this is our biggest
carelessness which costs us a lot in the
future.  And I would like to give you some more tips, one of which is
that if there are
small scratches or any small things on your car,
do not make an insurance claim because of that.  Insurance
claim is for emergency, that is,
if the damage is going out of your pocket or there is a
lot of damage and you feel
that it should be done from an authorized dealer only,
then you should do this work because
insurance is for emergency.  It is not
that you get a small scratch on your car and you
go to make a claim.  Because if you
sell the car in future, the complete
record of how many times you have made
insurance claim will be available there.  So
take special care of this and always get the
work done from an insurance approved garage.  So that your
process is very smooth and you do
not face any problem.  So you see, this process
is actually very simple.  If we know what to
do and when.
You should not panic after you have a car accident.
You have to take the photo quickly.   Have to
call the insurance company.  So that they
can make it intimate.  After that you have to
immediately return the car to your dealer.
If you are getting reimbursement then get it
fixed yourself.  If you first call the survey inspector
and do it cashless, then the
process is very smooth.  So you see,
this was very simple, very easy.   There is
no need for you to panic.
With the right knowledge you can do anything,
understand anything.  If you know how to handle each thing.
So guys, I
hope you enjoyed this video.
Please follow the correct vehicle.  So that
I can make your driving experience
smoother.  And until then I'll see
you next